<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DID Fall 2014</title>
    <description>Class website for DID Fall 2014</description>
    <link>http://teach.trvr.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://teach.trvr.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 15:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 15:00:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>DATA</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick Tip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-visualization&quot;&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualzation is a descriptive term that just means taking data, in the form of numbers usually, and turning it into something visual. While, hopefully, making it easy to understand as a visual metaphor. A lot of data is poorly visualized and therefore extremely hard to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week9/badgraph-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I... I just don't...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas! All is not lost, there are a lot of smart people using data for good. They understand that data is a powerful tool! And as we all know…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.comicvine.com/uploads/original/5/54400/1320070-cliff_robertson.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Uncle Ben&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With great power (er, data), comes great responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of people using data for good and making it easy to understand / comprehend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.good.is/infographics&quot;&gt;Good.is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dataveyes.com/&quot;&gt;Dataveyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;infographics&quot;&gt;Infographics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these websites have great examples of two types of data, infographics, and interactive data stories. You’ve all seen infographics before. They are big poster-like images that have a lot of pretty colors and numbers, and are the core of data vizualization. They are meant to to present complex sets of data quickly and with great ease, and have roots dating back to the early 1600s when astronomers first started cataloging the suns rotational patterns. As people started to grow the study of data visualization we start to get more complicated graphics. This one tracks 4 variables in a very elegant way showing Napoleons march on Moscow. It captured the direction the army traveled, the locations the troops passed through, the dwindling size of the army as they died, and the freezing tempuratures they experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/29/Minard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Charles Minard Shows Napoleon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More modern data scientists (this is what data visualizers often refer to themselves as) have started advancing the thinking and techniques that go into these visualizations. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Tufte&quot;&gt;Edward Tufte&lt;/a&gt; is a modern statistician (data guy) that has done a lot of great things for the field, and speaks often about information design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thumbnails-visually.netdna-ssl.com/all-scifi-spaceships-known-to-man_52448ad9767ff.jpg&quot;&gt;All kinds of spaceships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thumbnails-visually.netdna-ssl.com/ThePlanets_5282a6d2111c5.jpg&quot;&gt;Relative size of the planets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interactive-data-stories&quot;&gt;Interactive Data Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting things baout data design / visualization is how great it can be at telling stories. You might not look at a set of numbers in a spreadsheet and say. “Man, this looks like a great story” but really, that’s all it is. And if it isn’t telling a unique story, it’s helping advance or evolve storyline. It is the evidence needed to make you believe something, or put great weight on something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;politics&quot;&gt;Politics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guns.periscopic.com/?year=2013&quot;&gt;Guns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://drones.pitchinteractive.com/&quot;&gt;Drones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.therefugeeproject.org/&quot;&gt;The Refugee Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;social-commentary&quot;&gt;Social Commentary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://selfiecity.net/selfiexploratory/&quot;&gt;Selfie City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;musical&quot;&gt;Musical&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mta.me/&quot;&gt;Mta.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.baroque.me/&quot;&gt;Baroque.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-driven-design&quot;&gt;Data Driven Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently data has had a huge impact on design. It has taken the form of collecting analytics with services like Google Analytics and Mixpanel. These metrics are collected and used to make more informed design decisions about everything from what color a button should be to an entire architectural do-over, to complete website redesigns. Data allows us to have more confidence in the decisions we are making about pieces of our designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/analytics/&quot;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mixpanel.com/report/475085/events/&quot;&gt;Mixpanel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optimizely.com/&quot;&gt;Optimizely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clipping Masks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-time&quot;&gt;Work Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s work on project 2 for the rest of class. If you dont’ have to volley then you should use this time to gather resources for your next volley. Start planning ahead (even if you don’t know what it’s going to be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Visual-Display-Quantitative-Information/dp/0961392142/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1414551305&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=visual+display+of+quantitative&quot;&gt;Visual Display of Quantitative Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-02/&quot;&gt;COMPLETE Project 2 - Ping Pong&lt;/a&gt; – Due November 5th!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Modularity (pg 158 - 173)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STUDY&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;www.google.com/design/spec/material-design/&quot;&gt;Google Material Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-09</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-09</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>R-R-R-Remix</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1ZUAPdIwiwP-NG9e3ct6i9tJ0zbFOUtEEI0sLWW62d6Q/viewform&quot;&gt;Class Portfolios…WTH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Midterm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick Tip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity / Project 2 Start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;midterm----&quot;&gt;Midterm ┬─┬﻿ ︵ /(.□. \）&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take the first 30-45-ish minutes to complete the Midterm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-remix&quot;&gt;The Remix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A non-linear re-interpretation of a of a given work or media other than music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard of a remix before. It’s that version of a song that’s usually longer, more annoying, and bassier. Well, its roots are in music and back in the late 60’s and 70’s dancehall DJs would de-contsrturct popular music tracks and rebuild them to cater to their particular audiences. This reappropriation of other peoples sounds is what sparked the remix revolution. Remixes still permeate through the pop culture today, but, over the last 40 years the idea of the remix has been… remixed? o.O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remixing-in-pop-culture&quot;&gt;Remixing in Pop Culture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists do this thing a lot where they take some ideas from other artists and build ideas off of them. It’s not uncommon to see references of art history in modern art, or throwbacks to older songs in pop music. But some artists have taken this idea to a whole new level. Andy Warhol was particularly fond of this. Most of his work revolved around reappropriating consumer goods, or pop culture references by way of almost blantantly copying them, while simultaneously changing the context in which they are viewed (Art gallery walls instead of corner store shelves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/Marilyndiptych.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Andy Warhol loved remixes. He would re-appropriate modern objects and figures into pieces of pop art.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/remix-02.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edelmangallery.com/exhibitions-and-projects/exhibition-pages/2014/sandro-miller-malkovich,-malkovich,-malkovich-homage-to-photographic-masters.html&quot;&gt;Sandro&lt;/a&gt; has re-created some of the masters, but with John Malkovich&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imitation is the sincerest form of flattery, or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-cool-things&quot;&gt;Other Cool Things&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thru-you.com/&quot;&gt;Thru-You&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/thruyou.png&quot; alt=&quot;Thru-YOu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0OK3axoNrrA&quot;&gt;Flappy Bird Remakes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/flappy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Flappy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;copyright--fair-use&quot;&gt;Copyright &amp;amp; Fair Use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One extremely clear distinction to make with all of this talk about remixing and reappropriating is that it is &lt;strong&gt;ABSOLUTELY NOT&lt;/strong&gt; synonymous with plagiarism. That is still very much illegal, and will infringe on most college rules and copyright laws. If you consider doing any remix-y type stuff there are a few super important things that you should study to save you from copyright infringement because going to jail is bad. The first is The Copyright Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Copyright Act of 1976&lt;/strong&gt; is a United States copyright law and remains the primary basis of copyright law in the United States, as amended by several later enacted copyright provisions. The Act spells out the basic rights of copyright holders, codified the doctrine of &quot;fair use,&quot; and for most new copyrights adopted a unitary term based on the date of the author's death rather than the prior scheme of fixed initial and renewal terms. It became Public Law number 94-553 on October 19, 1976 and went into effect on January 1, 1978. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_1976&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next is Fair Use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fair use&lt;/strong&gt; is a limitation and exception to the exclusive right granted by copyright law to the author of a creative work. In United States copyright law, fair use is a doctrine that permits limited use of copyrighted material without acquiring permission from the rights holders. Examples of fair use include commentary, search engines, criticism, parody, news reporting, research, teaching, library archiving and scholarship. It provides for the legal, unlicensed citation or incorporation of copyrighted material in another author's work under a four-factor balancing test. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_use&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomforsythe.com/&quot;&gt;Tom Forsythe&lt;/a&gt; got sued by Mattel over the use of Barbie dolls in his project “Food Chain Barbie” but the case was dropped by Mattel because his use of the Barbies fell under the ‘parody’ clause of the Fair Use Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blending Modes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time--project-2---ping-pong&quot;&gt;Activity Time / Project 2 - Ping Pong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is going to kick-off Project 2. We are going to do something similar to Layer Tennis but without the commentary, and competition. What exactly is Layer Tennis you might ask? Well… &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.layertennis.com/&quot;&gt;It’s this thing&lt;/a&gt; that Jim Coudal and friends started a while ago here in Chicago. It has gotten really popular within the community and they are now on the 4th Season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;Two competitors swap a file back and forth in real-time, adding to and embellishing the work. Each artist gets fifteen minutes to complete a “volley” and then we post that to the site live. A third participant, a writer, provides play-by-play commentary on the action as it happens.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to change the rules a little bit to make it better suited for our class. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-02/&quot;&gt;The Project 2 Page&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://everythingisaremix.info/&quot;&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/kirby_ferguson_embrace_the_remix#t-556072&quot;&gt;Embrace the Remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-02/&quot;&gt;Start Project 2 - Mashup&lt;/a&gt; – Due November 5th!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Transparency (pg 146 - 157) and Texture (pg 52 - 69)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-08</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-08</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meaning &amp; Semiotics</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Critique&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Semiotics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;critique&quot;&gt;Critique&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s critique will be a bit different. We are going to pair up to critique 2 of the 5 sets of images. We will take 15 minutes to analyze and write about our partner’s images. After we write about them you will share your feedback with each other. &lt;em&gt;Ready&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Set&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Go&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;semiotics&quot;&gt;Semiotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking semiotics is a fancy word for the study of signs. Well, that’s cool… But what’s a sign? Signs are actually fairly complex. They are made up of any number of components – words, sounds, body language and context. Combined these create a sweet visual language that help us navigate the world, or read a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;Semioticians (yes there's a job for that) do this for a living.. They study signs and how they create meaning. They figure out how meaning can be derived from different cultural, or personal experience.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;icon-index-and-symbols&quot;&gt;Icon, Index, and Symbols&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, since there are people devoted to studying semiotics, someone was bound to classify, and categorize this stuff. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Sanders_Peirce&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; was that guy back in the early 1900s &lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/58/Charles_Sanders_Peirce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This one guy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To say, therefore, that thought cannot happen in an instant, but requires a time, is but another way of saying that every thought must be interpreted in another, or that all thought is in signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;large-block-grid-3 small-block-grid-1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Icon&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An Icon sign is a sign that resembles something, such as photographs of people. An icon can also be illustrative or diagrammatic, for example a ‘no-smoking’ sign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Index&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An Index signs are signs where there is a direct link between the sign and the object. The majority of traffic signs are Index signs as they represent information which relates to a location (eg, a ‘slippery road surface’ sign placed on a road which is prone to flooding)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Symbols&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A symbol has no logical meaning between it and the object. Unfortunately the web is littered with bad examples of this type of sign, but there are good ones - a homepage icon which is a house for example. Other off screen symbols which may help explain the difference are flags. Flags are symbols which represent countries or organisations. Again, the crossover to design and branding is very evident in these signs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;signifier-vs-signified&quot;&gt;Signifier vs Signified&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also another, arguably simpler, way to classify signs. Signifier, and signified. Or basically what the sign looks like, and what the sign means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Signifier’&lt;/strong&gt; - what it looks like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Signified’&lt;/strong&gt; - what it means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;group-activity-time&quot;&gt;Group Activity Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media0.giphy.com/media/xco6aabVXUQzC/200.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
We are going to split up into 4 groups and research one of these 4 symbols / icons below. Create a simple presentation (using Illustrator or Photoshop) which covers the history of it, it’s classification, it’s signifier and signified. You will then share it with us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handicapped Icon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace Sign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar Symbol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Cross Emblem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about it’s origins, how did it become culturally or historically relevant?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s sign classification (Icon, Index, Symbol)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s Signifier (What form does it take)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s Signified (What concept does it represent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blend tool! This powerful tool allows us to merge different shapes and styles together either on a smooth path, or with a specified amount of steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;midterm--&quot;&gt;Midterm (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.giphy.com/media/2FazfWOd7WPJuYqHe/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Aww Shit&quot; /&gt;
Im so into reaction gifs this week. And yes, we have a midterm. It’s going to be really really awesome and fun. I’ve even got a sweet study guide for you to use too. &lt;a href=&quot;/study-guides/midterm-guide/&quot;&gt;You can find that sweet guide right here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thenounproject.com&quot;&gt;The Noun Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rEgxTKUP_WI&quot;&gt;Sweet Semiotics Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Layers (pg 126 - 145)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STUDY&lt;/strong&gt; For Midterm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-07</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-07</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Framing</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Composition &amp;amp; Cropping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image &amp;amp; Canvas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/photo/1280/sealmaiden/660425083/1/tumblr_l34mioHhbi1qa4s0q&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Certain visual traces are like evidence. The event itself has passed but it has left information - marks, for example - and those marks are held there forever in time, like a photograph holds information as long as it lasts… It’s very mysterious to me to come upon something like that in reality and have it explain itself - to have it give evidence of what occurred then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;- Kenneth Josephson&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;composing&quot;&gt;Composing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve already covered on some of this when we talked about fundamental design theories a few weeks ago when we talked about &lt;a href=&quot;/week/week-02/#gestalt-theory&quot;&gt;Gestalt&lt;/a&gt; theories. The great thing about these concepts is that they can be used in any visual, or graphic art. Be that Print, Design, Illustration, or Game. We will focus a little more on these concepts and how they relate to photographs (photoshop eh?) but keep in mind that these are essentially universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rule-of-thirds&quot;&gt;Rule of thirds&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule of thirds is a framing concept that splits the frame vertically and horizontally 3 times creating 9 separate blocks. The most interesting part of this concept lies in how you use this grid. Science has proven, well that’s not totally true, that your pictures will be more compositionally pleasing if you align your subject on one of the intersecting points of your grid. Seems like a pretty rad and easy way to get some good snaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/rot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rule of thirds grid in action&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/rotsplit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It can also be used to organize your frame&lt;a href=&quot;http://photography.tutsplus.com/articles/quick-tip-the-rule-of-thirds--photo-7796&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;crop-tool&quot;&gt;Crop Tool&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t always have to align your subjects to the rule of thirds grid in your camera though. The Photoshop crop tool has some great grid overlays that allow you to re-frame any image to be more aligned with a grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;image--canvas&quot;&gt;Image &amp;amp; Canvas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One insanely important piece to all of this is understanding image size constraints (File size, and physical pixel dimensions of images), and how the canvas size plays into all of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;image-size&quot;&gt;Image Size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Image &amp;gt; Image Size&lt;/code&gt; will bring up the image size window. There are a few more complex things in here that we won’t be covering. But lets turn our attention to the width x height x resolution. Any image in Photoshop is defined by these three characteristics. Just as a room has width x height x depth a photograph is structured in a very similar way. One important thing to note is that images should never be up-sampled (made larger) than they originally were. This will basically make the image look like garbage and you’ll be bummed. The resolution, measured in PPI (Pixels Per Inch), is another critical piece of the images size. The larger the resolution, the more detail the image has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/image-size.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;canvas-size&quot;&gt;Canvas Size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Image &amp;gt; Canvas Size&lt;/code&gt; will open the Canvas Size dialog. Keep in mind that this is totally separate from image size, but can be used to make the area of the image larger or smaller. Imagine it just as it is described, like the canvas around a painting. Except you can grow or shrink this canvas willy nilly. This will never resize your image, but if you make the canvas smaller than your image it will basically crop it. Increasing the canvas size is really great when you want to add space around an image, or if you are creating a layout that needs extra margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/canvas-size.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google image search for some rad space image. Bring that image into photoshop and crop it align with a rule of thirds grid. Then we will add 100px to the canvas size of then image. And change the image size to be 80% of what it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://photography.tutsplus.com/articles/quick-tip-the-rule-of-thirds--photo-7796&quot;&gt;Rule of Thirds Quick Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vsco.co/vscocam&quot;&gt;VSCOcam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shootmanual.co/&quot;&gt;ShootManual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assignments/assignment-03.html&quot;&gt;Assignment 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt; Hierarchy (pg 114 - 125)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/Photoshop-tutorials/Honing-your-image/124096/140597-4.html&quot;&gt;Photoshop Tutorials - Watch all of section 6 starting with this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-06</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-06</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pixels</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/yu4CedbRRV&quot;&gt;Submit Your Class Portfolio Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project 1 Presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intro to Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro-to-photoshop&quot;&gt;Intro to Photoshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photoshop has long been the king of pixel manipulators. It has been man-handling those little digital squares since January of 1998. It is still considered THE premier digital photography application. Now, we also consider Photoshop to be an extremely powerful design tool. In fact many web and graphic designers use Photoshop to layout static comps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vector-vs-raster-bitmap&quot;&gt;Vector vs Raster (Bitmap)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know from Illustrator vector lines are extremely accurate and are drawn by math. With raster all lines, shapes, and images are drawn with little dots on the screen, pixels. On a large image the detail created with these pixels can make up a photographic image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/vector-raster.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This is what raster and vector look like @ 400% zoom.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rgb-colorspace&quot;&gt;RGB Colorspace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked a little about Illustrator’s colorspace defaults to CMYK (subtractive color). Photoshop is on the other end and defaults to RGB. Primarily because photography deals with light (additive color). You’ll see this if you open up the Channels palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/cmykrgb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This is what raster and vector look like @ 400% zoom.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-of-photoshop&quot;&gt;Benefits of Photoshop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the major benefits of Photoshop vs Vector programs really comes down to it’s ability to edit raster images. It makes designing photographic layouts much easier since you have the ability to edit the photos and lay them out in the same application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/mailchimp_redesign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mailchimps last redesign would have been a pain without something like Photoshop.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on the flip side, images contain a whole lot more data than vector files so your file sizes start to get significantly larger. I’ve had comps that will get well above the 1GB file size range. That’s not always fun when you have a deadline, and it takes 10 minutes to save a file :\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;photoshop-workspace&quot;&gt;Photoshop Workspace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at some of the tools we’ve got in the Photoshop UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/ps-107.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The photoshop Toolbar. LOLJKROFLMAO.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JK, that’s the Photoshop 1.0 UI. It’s changed a lot, for realsies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/photoshop-tools.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Phew, I found them. This is what PS CC looks like. CS6 will look a little bit different.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/week5/ps-activity-01.psd&quot;&gt;Download this file&lt;/a&gt;, we will work from this and learn about some of the more important photoshop tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;photoshop-alternatives&quot;&gt;Photoshop Alternatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pretty rad alternatives to Photoshop. &lt;strong&gt;HUGE DISCLAIMER: I don’t know all these apps so if you want to use them you will be kind of on your own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pixelmator.com/&quot;&gt;Pixelmator (Mac only)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bohemiancoding.com/sketch/&quot;&gt;Sketch (Mac Only)&lt;/a&gt; - This is not a photoeditor, but it’s the application that I use for UI design. It’s pretty rad, and is great for webdesign .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No Assignments Just reading and tutorials to make you more awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Framing (pg 100 - 113)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/Photoshop-tutorials/Navigating-your-image/124096/140551-4.html&quot;&gt;Photoshop Tutorials - Watch all of section 2 starting with this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-05</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-05</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&lt; H T M L &gt;</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;H T M L&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C S S&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start Class portfolios / Show me some Project 1 stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;h-y-p-e-r-t-e-x-t-m-a-r-k-u-p-l-a-n-g-u-a-g-e&quot;&gt;H Y P E R T E X T M A R K U P L A N G U A G E&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-basix&quot;&gt;The Basix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language) is a markup language for the web. All websites you visit are built with HTML, and it is nothing more than a dumbed down word processor. Srsly, that’s how HTML was created, to share scientific documents between labs that were around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.isoc-ny.org/p2/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/timbernerslee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This dude invented what you know as the World Wide Web (does anyone call it that?)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;let’s watch a quick video that will dive into ta bit of the history of HTML and the web. &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/12020260&quot;&gt;Video Time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;html-breakdown&quot;&gt;HTML Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific version of HTML we are learning is 5. And HTML5 is actually pretty simple and HTML elements are pretty basic and easy to remember. Say you have a big block of text, a paragraph!, you would wrap that block of text in tags that look like this &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;BIG BLOCK OF TEXT&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; in this example is an HTML tag. All HTML tags start with &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;TAG&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and close with &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/TAG&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Let’s take a look at some &lt;code&gt;CODE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is literally all you need to create an HTML document. This is the start of every single website on the internet. What’s your favorite website? I’ll bet it uses this format. And there are all kinds of tags. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;section&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;video&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and that’s just a few. I bet you could guess what some of those do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That example above won’t display anything when we put it into the browser because there’s no content. So lets add a few other things. How about an image and some paragraph text?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; Here&amp;#39;s some paragraph text. Such compelling. So paragraph. Wow.&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://placekitten.com/600/350&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;c-a-s-c-a-d-i-n-g-s-t-y-l-e-s-h-e-e-t-s&quot;&gt;C A S C A D I N G S T Y L E S H E E T S&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet, we’ve made a dope HTML Document! But, man, it’s friggen ugly right? Well that’s where CSS comes in. CSS allows you to attach some nice styles to your HTML elements. If you think about a house, HTML is the walls and CSS is the paint. Say you want the background to be hot pink, because hot pink. And we want the text to be blue, since it will make our brains melt. But how does it look? CSS can attach itself to specific HTML elements to make them look different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECTOR { DECLARATION – PROPERTY : VALUE }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;pink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-specific&quot;&gt;Getting specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While styling tags is all cool and stuff, the real power of CSS comes in with Classes and IDs. These are semantic identifiers for HTML tags. For example. If I had a block of text that we wanted to be purple but we didn’t want every single &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag to be purple we could give that tag a class of purple. And it would look like this &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;purple-text&quot;&amp;gt;THIS IS PURPLE TEXT&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Then go into your CSS file and add this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.purple-text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;pink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the one weird thing about this is there is a &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; before the words &lt;code&gt;purple-text&lt;/code&gt;. That &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; defines a CSS class. Try and keep you classes semantic and easy to understand. When you see purple text in a CSS file it’s pretty clear what that does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s do this next section together. Download &lt;a href=&quot;/files/week4/class-site-template.zip&quot;&gt;this file&lt;/a&gt;, and open up the &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file in any text editor. We will start creating our class portfolios. WOOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;choose-your-path-to-deploy-or-not-deploy&quot;&gt;Choose your path. To deploy or not deploy.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since we aren’t going to get a whole lot deeper with HTML I don’t think it’s 100% necessary for all of you to create your own HTML pages. However, I will support your decision to do so. I’ll also give you the option to create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;tumblr&lt;/a&gt; for yourself / this class. So if you are making a new tumblr account go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tumblr.com/register&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt;. If you have a tumblr account already, create a new blog for this class in the dashboard. If you plan to create your own HTML site KEEP ON READIN’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imamp.colum.edu/mediawiki/index.php/FTP#IAM_tech_staff_recommends_connecting_to_our_server_with_FTPs_please_see_the_FTPs_tutorial_IAM_FTPS_Tutorial&quot;&gt;Re-learn to FTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are on the network, and on a PC, go to your Z drive. This is your space on IAM servers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In your pub folder, create a subfolder called DID.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload all the files we worked on to that folder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to your URL&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload or add your work to your portfolio! This is a graded piece of the class and will be required to upload your work your portfolios. Add the assignments you’ve already done with a &lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;short description&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/courses/web-beginner-en-HZA3b/0/1?curriculum_id=50579fb998b470000202dc8b&quot;&gt;Do this Codecadmy activity to upgrade your HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read: Figure / Ground (pg 84 - 99)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-01.html&quot;&gt;PROJECT 01&lt;/a&gt; – Next week we will present your first Projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;Code Cademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeschool.com/&quot;&gt;CodeSchool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/HTML-CSS-Design-Build-Websites/dp/1118008189/ref=sr_1_1/191-9246497-5557808?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1411606712&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=html+css&quot;&gt;Great HTML &amp;amp; CSS book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://html5boilerplate.com/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-04</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-04</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Color &amp; Type</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic Color Theory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding Type&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start Project 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;first-color-theory&quot;&gt;First, Color Theory&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color. Color is a HUGE huge huge concept. Actually both color and type are huge huge huge concepts. But, we are gonna tackle them both since &lt;strong&gt;YOU DEFINITELY ALL READ THE COLOR CHAPTER SO I DON’T EVEN REALLY NEED TO COVER THIS VERY MUCH RIGHT?&lt;/strong&gt; And because we are awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;large-block-grid-3 small-block-grid-1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Color Wheel&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shows relationships between colors. All dem colors.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/hue.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Primary Colors&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These are mixed to make all other colors. Can’t be made from other colors.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/primary.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Secondary Colors&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Two primary colors mixed together create secondary colors.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/secondary.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Tertiary Colors&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Created with one primary and one secondary color mixed together.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/tertiary.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Complementary&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Opposite each other on the color wheel. Think Christmas, Da Bears, or The Lakers&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/complimentary.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Analogous Colors&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the same section, or very near each other, on the color wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/analogous.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;color-attributes&quot;&gt;Color Attributes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hue:&lt;/strong&gt; An element of the color wheel (ROYGBV)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intensity:&lt;/strong&gt; How bright or dull a color is. Intensity changes with a change in saturation, shading, and/or tinting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturation:&lt;/strong&gt; Purity of a color when neutralizing to grey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value:&lt;/strong&gt; How light or dark the color is.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shade:&lt;/strong&gt; hue + black&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tint:&lt;/strong&gt; hue + white&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;color-models-aka-color-space&quot;&gt;Color Models (aka Color Space)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMYK:&lt;/strong&gt; Cyan, magenta, yellow, and black. Printing/pigments. Subtractive (pigments absorb light, subtracting certain wavelengths of light from our visible spectrum)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RGB:&lt;/strong&gt; Red, green, blue. On screen. Additive. All three colors at full strength creates white light, while black is the absence of light.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;color-effects&quot;&gt;Color Effects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bezold Effect:&lt;/strong&gt; Optical mixing, an optical illusion wherein a color appears lighter or darker based on what color it is adjacent to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vibration and Value:&lt;/strong&gt; A color placed on another color close in value can appear to “glow”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;and-now-type&quot;&gt;And now: Type&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/anatomy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Memorize this. If I ever quiz you on things, this will be on that quiz&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;large-block-grid-2 small-block-grid-1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Typeface&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A family of fonts. AKA All of Avenir is the Typeface, a font is Avenir Light&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/typeface.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Size&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Size refers to how big the font is in a unit of measure. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/font-size.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Weight&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The weight of the font, usually defined as light, regular, or bold.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/font-weight.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Tracking&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Defines the space between characters in a word. This is not the same as Kerning.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/tracking.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Leading&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is the space between lines of text. Imagine a strip of lead resting between the lines&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/leading.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Kerning&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The space between individual characters. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcodesign.com/3035334/fast-feed/esurance-learns-an-expensive-lesson-on-why-kerning-matters&quot;&gt;This is why kerning matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/kerning.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-time&quot;&gt;Game Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://type.method.ac/&quot;&gt;http://type.method.ac/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shape.method.ac/&quot;&gt;http://shape.method.ac/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bezier.method.ac/&quot;&gt;http://bezier.method.ac/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;type-has-personality&quot;&gt;Type has personality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every font has a personality, and an opnion. Sometimes, just like with real people, different fonts will have stronger personality traits. Every font will be able to tell a story about itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/type-regal.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Lust Didone is super regal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/type-sturdy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Merriweather is a solid typeface&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/type-overt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Some are very unique&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/type-stylized.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Duke is very unique, and strong&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/type-comical.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I had to...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When choosing a typeface you really need to think about the message you want to get across. You aren’t going to write going to make a metal show poster in comic sans. Unless you are a super troll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;type-in-illustrator&quot;&gt;Type in Illustrator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typograpy in Illustrator is another strong use-case for it’s popularity, and power. Here is a breakdown of the Type Tool Palette&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/type-tool.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The elusive Illustrator type tool&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Type out your favorite movie / game / whatever quote and we will set (set is the fancymans word for making type look good) it in illustrator using all the type tool has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Goonies never say die. / Do the truffle shuffle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two quotes from my favorite movie. Someone else in this room better love this movie…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week3/chunk.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Proof of my goonie-wisdom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice Class Activities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read: Rhythm &amp;amp; Balance and Scale (pg 28 - 51)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-01.html&quot;&gt;PROJECT 01 (PROGRESS)&lt;/a&gt; – Minimal movie poster, game cover, or book cover. Show me sketches &amp;amp; concept&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/extra-credit/extra-credit-01.html&quot;&gt;10 Examples of good typography in the wild (Extra Credit)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kuler.adobe.com/create/color-wheel/&quot;&gt;Adobe Kuler&lt;/a&gt; - Create color palettes, schemes. Integrates with adobe apps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://losttype.com&quot;&gt;Lost Type Co&lt;/a&gt; - A co-op type foundry on the nannernet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://avondaletypeco.com/&quot;&gt;Avondale type Co&lt;/a&gt; - An awesome local type foundry located in Avondale (not free, but good type isn’t free)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://typekict.com&quot;&gt;Typekit&lt;/a&gt; - If you have an Adobe CC account you get one of these with it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://justmytype.co/&quot;&gt;Just my type&lt;/a&gt; - Good resource for pairing fonts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thinkingwithtype.com/&quot;&gt;http://thinkingwithtype.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-03</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-03</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building Blocks</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Homework Review / Critique&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gestalt Theory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gestalt Principles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pen tool activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gestalt-theory&quot;&gt;Gestalt Theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The whole is other than the sum of the parts” - Kurt Koffka&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gestalt theory is the basis of how we visually perceive objects. In essence, when we see a group of objects, we perceive the whole before we consider it’s parts. And even when we look at the parts we want to group them as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-properties---aka-the-list-of-crazy-words&quot;&gt;Key Properties - AKA The list of crazy words&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;large-block-grid-2 small-block-grid-1&quot;&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Emergence&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is basically pattern recognition. We see the outline of a shape, identify that shape, then we begin to recognize the parts that make up the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/emergence.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;What shape emerges?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Reification&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is filling in the gaps. If there isn’t enough visual data present we will make up the missing information in our minds to create something meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/reification.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Shapes without a definitive shape&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Multi-stability&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Describes what our mind does when it sees two things within one image. We cannot focus on both images, so we only see one at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/multistability.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;One or two images?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Invariance&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The ability to recognize shapes at various angles. This is due to our seeing things in three dimensions. We’ve adapted to recognizing in different contexts.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/invariance.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It's always a box with a hole in it&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gestalt-principles&quot;&gt;Gestalt Principles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everything we do in graphic design is summarized in these theories and principles. Understanding all of the principles below will make you an ultimate design badass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“People will perceive and interpret ambiguous or complex images as the simplest form(s) possible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;large-block-grid-4 small-block-grid-1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Law of Prägnanz&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/law-of-pragnanz.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The fundamental principle, we prefer simple, clear, and ordered images. They take less time to recognize and are easier to interperet.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Closure&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/closure.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We generally look for a single recognizable pattern in images. Often completing images where there may be missing information.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Figure / Ground&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/figure-ground.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Elements are perceived as either in focus (the foreground of the images) or resting (the background).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Uniform Connectedness&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/uniform-connectedness.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Similar elements, line, shape, and color grouped together can be visually connected as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Good Continuation&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/good-continuation.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Elements appearing in a line or a curve are percieved to be more related than elements not on the line or curve.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Common Fate&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/common-fate.gif&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We tend to percieve images moving in the same direction as being more related. &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Proximity&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/proximity.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Things that are close to each other are more easily relatable than things that are not close.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Similarity&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/similarity.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Things that are similar to each other are more easily relatable than things that are not similar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-pen-tool&quot;&gt;The Pen Tool&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s enough concepts for now. Let’s dig into one of Illustrators most powerful features. The Pen tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/pen-tool.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This should probably be a t-shirt&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;breaking-down-the-pen-tool&quot;&gt;Breaking down the pen tool&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a funny thing. It’s simultaneously one of the most powerful tools in Illustrator and it starts out kind of complex, but then becomes really simple and intuitive. The first thing to understand is the Bezier Curve!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/bezier-curve.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;All them curves&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bezier Curve is the main reason the pen tool was so innovative when Illustrator first came out. It allowed artists to create accurate, curvy, organic lines in a pretty easy way. Let’s talk really quick about some of the different options within the pen tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week2/pen-tool-options.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Some of the options we are going to cover.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Pen Tool. We are going to run through a quick and dirty pen tool exercise. &lt;a href=&quot;/files/week2/Pen_Tool_The_Exercise.ai&quot;&gt;Download This File&lt;/a&gt;, open it up in illustrator, and we should be good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice Class Activities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read: Color (pg 70-83)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read: &lt;a href=&quot;http://design.tutsplus.com/articles/a-20-minute-intro-to-typography-basics--psd-3326&quot;&gt;Intro to Typography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/Illustrator-tutorials/tool-can-draw-anything/124100/142940-4.html&quot;&gt;These Lynda Illustrator Tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assignments/assignment-02.html&quot;&gt;Selfies - Click for assignment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/illustrators-pen-tool-the-comprehensive-guide--vector-141&quot;&gt;Comprehensive Pen Tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thinkingwithtype.com/&quot;&gt;Thinking with Type&lt;/a&gt; – Comprehensive type nerdfest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webtypography.net/&quot;&gt;Elements of Typographic Style&lt;/a&gt; – The definitive type manual applied to the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 09:18:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-02</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-02</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome!!</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://slides.com/trevormcnaughton/hi/live#/&quot;&gt;Introductions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/DID-36-1300-03-fa14.pdf&quot;&gt;Review Syllabus&lt;/a&gt; – Subject to change!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/15oZegSzd82MabpNdfJdHLbSLTadkHdjCUbBb8Bx-Xo4/viewform?usp=send_form&quot;&gt;First Day Survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Illustrator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-to-illustrator&quot;&gt;Introduction to Illustrator&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Illustrator is a super powerful drawing program. It is part of the Adobe Creative Cloud, and will be the first application we learn to use. It is mostly used to draw illustrations, cartoons, logos, and interfaces. It uses mathematical equations to draw lines, shapes, and colors. Meaning anything you make with illustrator is scalable without any loss of resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/logo-examples.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Vector logo examples&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/character-examples.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Some vector characters&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/interface-examples.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A couple rad interfaces&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this gives you an idea of some of the things we are capable of building with illustrator. It’s a very powerful tool, and has a whole lot of nuances. Don’t get overwhelmed, we will tackle it piece by piece. Starting from the very beginning. Creating a new file. Below is the basic rundown of what we will cover first. Don’t worry, things will get more exciting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First we will create a new document. &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;New&lt;/code&gt; and make a new Letter Document (8.5x11 inches). We will just use the default settings for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/ai-new-doc.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The new file interface&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can open an image file within Illustrator via &lt;code&gt;File&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code&gt;Open&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at some of the User Interface (UI). There’s a lot here and you won’t be expected to memorize all of it right away. This toolbar is going to be one of your best friends over the next few weeks. Get to know it, and love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/ai-toolbar.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrator Toolbar&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets make some faces with the basic Illustrator tools. Using only the line tool, and shape tools, lets put together a few quick faces. Try playing with different stroke thicknesses, and different shape sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/activity-shapes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;What can we make using just these shapes?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shape-faces&quot;&gt;Shape Faces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was difficult about it? Were the rules helpful or too much of a constraint?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week1/activity-shape-faces.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;You don't always need to render detailed images to get an idea across&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice Class Activities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read: Point, Line, and Plane (pg 12-27)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch: Illustrator tutorials on Lynda.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assignments/assignment-01.html&quot;&gt;Assignment 1 – Digital Sketches&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;notes--extra-stuff&quot;&gt;Notes &amp;amp; Extra stuff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://design.tutsplus.com/tutorials/illustrators-pen-tool-the-comprehensive-guide--vector-141&quot;&gt;Comprehensive Pen Tool Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 09:18:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-01</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-01</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
