<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DID Fall 2014</title>
    <description>Class website for DID Fall 2014</description>
    <link>http://teach.trvr.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://teach.trvr.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 18:08:39 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 18:08:39 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wrap Up</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-time&quot;&gt;Work Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we’ll have a mega productive work session (because I bet some of you could use it :D). Feel free to ask me any questions, now is your chance, BECAUSE IT’S THE LAST CLASS NEXT WEEK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://asset-d.soup.io/asset/3076/5936_d42e.gif&quot; alt=&quot;SAAAAAD&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;ALSO: Some of ya'll have been leaving early during worktime. That's not cool, and is actually considered late on your attendance if you havent cleared it with me! So, let's not do that today.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img4.wikia.nocookie.net/__cb20121007102258/glee/images/2/26/Teamwork.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Teamwork&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/final-project&quot;&gt;Finish Final Project!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-14</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-14</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Animation</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Animation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a UI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some Cool Stuff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity / Quick Tip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;making-things-move&quot;&gt;Making things move&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we’ve worked mostly in two dimensions and almost exclusively with computer screens. But today, we shall travel straight past the third dimension and &lt;strong&gt;INTO THE FOURTH&lt;/strong&gt;. Time.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.gimpbible.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/02/gimpbible-f1901.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Time&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;XYZTime&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is so interesting because it describes how things go from here to there, and change from this to that. It helps our brains think about states, changes, adding, subtracting. It helps us rationalize things happening on the screen by giving our feeble minds feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://38.media.tumblr.com/7c00abe58738a66ce9e37ad46665946f/tumblr_nbt7s4tXG01rf78nfo1_400.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Shapes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Movement also creates delight, when done correctly. When done poorly it makes you cringe. It is souless and gross, and often is because computers interpolate movement in a straight line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Computers are jerks and love to fill in the gaps linearly because they are lazy sacks of wires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@pasql/transitional-interfaces-926eb80d64e3&quot;&gt;Pasquale D’Silva&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you think of an animation either in an app, or a game, or a movie, that made you feel awesome? Or is just straight up awesome?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disney&quot;&gt;Disney&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disney was the pioneer of animation, and the 12 fundamentals that Disney created still hold true for modern animators today (both in cartooning, interface, motion graphics, and game). Those 12 principles are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Squash and stretch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anticipation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Staging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Straight ahead action and pose to pose&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow through and overlapping action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slow in and slow out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arcs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secondary action&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exaggeration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solid drawing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Appeal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen vimeo&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/93206523&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/93206523&quot;&gt;The illusion of life&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/centodesign&quot;&gt;cento lodigiani&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;motion-graphics&quot;&gt;Motion Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen youtube&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/VpZmIiIXuZ0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Advertisement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intersection of graphic design, and animation is basically motion graphics. It is very much what the name sounds like. The popularization of motions graphics has been helped by mainstream applications like After Effects, and Cinema 4D. Both applications make it easier for designers to create pretty moving shapes, and characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;animation-in-ui&quot;&gt;Animation in UI&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen youtube&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/TMe0WnkF1Lc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Designing With Motion: Pasquale D’Silva&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important jobs for animation in our interface is to give us important feedback on what is happening to the UI in front of you. What does a button do when you press it? How does the next screen in an interface come in? Does it just appear? Or does it scale in and up from the bottom? Animation reveals information about where things come from, and how they work. It is a very important piece in helping users understand how things work. Animation provides cues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/design/spec/animation/authentic-motion.html&quot;&gt;Google Design – Authentic Motion&lt;/a&gt;
Google thinks that animation should feel authentic. That it should be responsive and make the interface feel more alive. They do so in a number of ways, but mostly updating and changing the interface when a user interacts with elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen&quot;&gt;
&lt;video src=&quot;http://material-design.storage.googleapis.com/publish/v_2/material_ext_publish/0B2wX4iIvu8L6aHVOOGxBOW5jZlE/animation-meaningfultransitions-visualcontinuity_music-tablet-01_xhdpi.webm&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google Material Design: Authentic Motion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot happening in that video, but pay attention to where things are coming from, how elements are responding, and how animation is assisting in the understanding of the interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;oh-and-games&quot;&gt;Oh and Games!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen youtube&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/5K4zjNtQ3y8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Was Alone&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen youtube&quot;&gt;
	&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/TYarBbOtlzc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dots: A Game About Connecting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;easing--cushoning&quot;&gt;Easing &amp;amp; Cushoning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easing is a huge part of making animation feel more organic and fluid. Things IRL don’t just move from here to there at the exact same pace. When you drop a ball on the ground it accellerates. It’s animation quickens as it approaches the ground because gravity is pulling on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1600/0*yfq40i7GG4MDdzzA.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Ease In&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d262ilb51hltx0.cloudfront.net/max/1600/0*LKq1k9BrgDRRqoMR.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Ease Out&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cool-stuff&quot;&gt;Cool Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen vimeo&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/1QAI4B_2Mfc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flex-video widescreen vimeo&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.vimeo.com/video/62998334&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/62998334&quot;&gt;demo 2013&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/setheckert&quot;&gt;Seth Eckert&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity--tip&quot;&gt;Activity / Tip&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple easing in After Effects!!!!! We will do this together, and bear with me. I haven’t used AE in a while…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-on-finals&quot;&gt;Work on Finals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use the rest of class as time to work on our finals. Ask me questions, and no you can’t leave early because I know you have stuff you can work on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-week&quot;&gt;Next week&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt; Next week we will not have class, because Thanksgiving and I’ll be travelling. &lt;strong&gt;THIS DOES NOT MEAN&lt;/strong&gt; you can slack for a week. You will be expected to complete any work I assign, and to go through what we are covering on your own. I also will need to see progress on what you will be doing for your final projects. You will be expected to turn in your progress on Moodle so I can see how your projects are coming along. Also, don’t forget that &lt;strong&gt;these steps are graded towards your final!&lt;/strong&gt; If you are late with your check-ins this will affect your grade on your final. If it is unclear what we discussed for your check-in see me and we can get it squared away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://markgeyer.com/pres/the-art-of-ui-animations/&quot;&gt;UI Animation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://framerjs.com/&quot;&gt;FramerJS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://daneden.github.io/animate.css/&quot;&gt;Animate.css&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motionaddicts.com/&quot;&gt;Motion Addicts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sixux.com/&quot;&gt;Six UX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://the12principles.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;The 12 Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@sureshvselvaraj/animation-principles-in-ui-design-understanding-easing-bea05243fe3&quot;&gt;Animation Principles in UI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/user-experience-design-1/the-anatomy-of-a-grid-c955d5355fae&quot;&gt;Some More Grid Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Time &amp;amp; Motion (pg 214 - 231)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/final-project&quot;&gt;Turn in Final check-in progress (on moodle)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-12</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-12</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Grid</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grids n Things&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity / Start Assignment / Final Project 1:1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;grids&quot;&gt;Grids&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://33.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m96evkFN6Q1rtbmngo1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;The Grid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I tried to picture clusters of information as they moved through the computer. What did they look like? Ships? motorcycles? Were the circuits like freeways? I kept dreaming of a world I thought I’d never see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this class has nothing to do with Tron. Whenever I hear or say “The Grid” I think of that quote. I know. &lt;strong&gt;#COOLSTORYBRO&lt;/strong&gt;. Like most of these topics, grids have been around for a super long time. And they are defined as a two-dimensional structure made up of intersecting lines. It is a powerful tool for a designer because it lets us organize content in a meaningful, and rational manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-lil-history&quot;&gt;A Lil History&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layouts date back to the first introduction of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Movable_type&quot;&gt;Movable Type&lt;/a&gt;, because it allowed type to be reproduced accurately and basically infinitely (this was also the reason books were being printed and published en-masse). Since type could be re-created type setters could be a bit more mathematical, and systematic about their layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week11/first-layouts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First Layouts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Some of the first book layouts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-bauhaus&quot;&gt;The Bauhaus&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But typographic layouts had pretty much stayed the same from then until around World War 1 and the Bauhaus School. We aren’t going to talk a lot about this specific school and movement. But just know that it shook the design world up in a really good way. Especially for graphic and typographic design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week11/bauhaus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bauhaus Movement&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Then came The Bauhaus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bauhaus basically wanted to take all of these old, rigid rules of design and creating and dismantle them, break them down, and re-assemble them in a new way. It was totally avant-garde and super refreshing ( or controversial ) for it’s time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;swiss-international-design&quot;&gt;Swiss (International) Design&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years after the Bauhaus was making waves in art and design a group of constructivist modernist designers emerged with a great call to action and definition for this new style of design. The Swiss style was an authentic pursuit of simplicity. This spanned across a multitude of mediums including graphic design, and architecture. It wanted to focus more on the simplistic shapes and forms, and less on texture and illustration (in terms of graphic design).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week11/swiss.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swiss Design&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;One of my favorite design movements. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/20745656@N00/sets/72157594296535170/&quot;&gt;Here’s a good visual overview of early Swiss Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see that it’s very pragmatic, and clear. There is a very defined structure and it almost completely relies on typography and a rigid grid. Let’s look at one of those images with a grid overlay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week11/swiss-grid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swiss Design&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;See how nicely everything sit on something?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look how this grid works. It’s super simple, consistent gutters, fixed width columns. Everything feels study and supported even though the grid is essentially negative space. And keep in mind this is all being done without computers :O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week11/swiss-grid-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swiss Design&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And here’s another good example. See how they all sit on a perpendicular grid? and how the large letterform defines the base of the grid?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-web-design&quot;&gt;In Web Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine grids are an amazing and powerful tool for web designers as well. Most websites you visit are build upon some type of grid system. Back in my day the most popular grid system for web designers was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://960.gs/&quot;&gt;960 grid&lt;/a&gt;. Which is a 12 or 16  column pixel based grid system. It became so popular because it was really easy to use, and it was extremely powerful. And as screens got bigger so did browser windows, so we opened our minds to a larger default, the (1140px grid)[http://www.1140px.com/]. But this also became limited, because at the same time that screens were getting larger. They were also getting smaller. Cue, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abookapart.com/products/responsive-web-design&quot;&gt;Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt;. This threw a number of new problems at designers. And we are nothing if not problem solvers. So all of the grid we had previously build had to become flexible to accomodate not just computer screens but all kinds of mobile screens and devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sacred-grids&quot;&gt;Sacred Grids&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the last stop on this grid train is a different kind of grid. They are grids that i’ve mentioned before and have been around longer than most of these layouts. The first one is Metatrons Cube, mah favorite. It consists of 13 circles each with a line originating from the center to the other 12 circles. And it creates this badass grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/31/Metatron_solids.svg/1920px-Metatron_solids.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Metatrons Cubes&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Various grids based of similar platonic solids&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more commonly used grid, is one based of the devine number Phi. This golden rectangle has been used in fine art and design for centures. And will continue to be used as it creates pleasing compositions, and is very dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/22/Whirling_squares.svg/915px-Whirling_squares.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Golden Rectangle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Golden Rectangle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a grid in Photoshop / Illustrator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://historyofart.mijlo.com/&quot;&gt;History of Art in 100 Words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://apps.npr.org/lookatthis/posts/colors/&quot;&gt;NPR Colors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://foundation.zurb.com/&quot;&gt;Zurb Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/aosmialowski/1140px-Responsive-CSS-Grid/raw/master/psd/1140px_12Col_10Gutter.psd&quot;&gt;1140px grid PSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/assignments/assignment-04&quot;&gt;Assignment 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/final-project&quot;&gt;Work on Final Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Diagram (pg 198 - 213)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-11</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-11</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interface</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project 2 Critique&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interface&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;interface&quot;&gt;Interface&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interface is literally described as a point where two systems interact. An axe is an interface between your arms and chopping wood. A controller is an interface between your hands and pwning n00bz on your console. A button on your screen is an interface between your cursor (you) and an action you wish to complete. Buttons are an extremely important piece in a GUI (Graphical User Interface, or just User Interface for short), and you probably use them several times a day. &lt;strong&gt;Can you name any other important pieces of a User Interface?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;apple-vs-xerox&quot;&gt;Apple vs Xerox&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first UIs was created in 1982, by none other than… Wait for it… Xerox. Yes the company that makes scanners, and printers. They invented the concept of the Desktop, and the mouse to interact with this new graphical interface. They were ahead of their time and inspired Steve Jobs to essentially rip it off. Jobs then designed the first Apple desktop interface and made it sound like something completely new and innovative. Sound familiar? Xerox sued Apple for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/1989/12/15/business/company-news-xerox-sues-apple-computer-over-macintosh-copyright.html&quot;&gt;$150 Million back in 1989&lt;/a&gt;, but was eventually dismissed because the courts did not seem to think you could copyright something like an interface. The concepts that Xerox created in this first iteration are still visible in the modern desktop interface, even down to how they’ve named the pieces of UI and good deal of icons. Some might say that it was timeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.logodesignlove.com/images/classic/xerox-logo-tom-geismar.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Xerox&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cn4vC80Pv6Q&quot;&gt;Xerox Star UI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;but-what-makes-an-interface-good&quot;&gt;But What Makes an Interface Good?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the eternal question. &lt;strong&gt;What are some good interfaces? What makes them good? What elements make you feel attached to them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ui-patterns-in-modern-interface-design&quot;&gt;UI Patterns in Modern Interface Design&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patterns, in User Experience (UX) and User Interface design, are defined as formal ways to document a solution to a common design problem. There have been a few patterns in app and website design recently that have surpassed many other solutions. The Hamburger Menu (or off canvas menu) is one example of a UI pattern that has had so much traction that it is all but ubiquitous in mobile apps and websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn4.iconfinder.com/data/icons/wirecons-free-vector-icons/32/menu-alt-512.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Hamburger&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve seen it, you’ve used it. But how do you feel about it? It has been a great solution for many designers because of the problem it solves. But what exactly is that problem? Some say that it majorily been used as a crutch… And many a designer think that the Hamburger is synonymous with simplistic, or minimal design. But often minimal (at least with this example) can border on the edge of bad usablity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tasteful drop shadows!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;Activity Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s make a quick interface. Let’s design a minimal music player app with just the bare essentials. Make a 800x600px @ 72ppi document in Photoshop or Illustrator. Make sure it includes the following elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Artist Name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Song Title&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play Button&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next &amp;amp; Last buttons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/final-project&quot;&gt;Final Project Proposals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Grid &amp;amp; Pattern (pg 174 - 197)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-10</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-10</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DATA</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick Tip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work Time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-visualization&quot;&gt;Data Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualzation is a descriptive term that just means taking data, in the form of numbers usually, and turning it into something visual. While, hopefully, making it easy to understand as a visual metaphor. A lot of data is poorly visualized and therefore extremely hard to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week9/badgraph-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I... I just don't...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas! All is not lost, there are a lot of smart people using data for good. They understand that data is a powerful tool! And as we all know…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://static.comicvine.com/uploads/original/5/54400/1320070-cliff_robertson.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Uncle Ben&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;With great power (er, data), comes great responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of people using data for good and making it easy to understand / comprehend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://magazine.good.is/infographics&quot;&gt;Good.is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dataveyes.com/&quot;&gt;Dataveyes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;infographics&quot;&gt;Infographics&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each of these websites have great examples of two types of data, infographics, and interactive data stories. You’ve all seen infographics before. They are big poster-like images that have a lot of pretty colors and numbers, and are the core of data vizualization. They are meant to to present complex sets of data quickly and with great ease, and have roots dating back to the early 1600s when astronomers first started cataloging the suns rotational patterns. As people started to grow the study of data visualization we start to get more complicated graphics. This one tracks 4 variables in a very elegant way showing Napoleons march on Moscow. It captured the direction the army traveled, the locations the troops passed through, the dwindling size of the army as they died, and the freezing tempuratures they experienced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/29/Minard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Charles Minard Shows Napoleon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More modern data scientists (this is what data visualizers often refer to themselves as) have started advancing the thinking and techniques that go into these visualizations. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edward_Tufte&quot;&gt;Edward Tufte&lt;/a&gt; is a modern statistician (data guy) that has done a lot of great things for the field, and speaks often about information design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thumbnails-visually.netdna-ssl.com/all-scifi-spaceships-known-to-man_52448ad9767ff.jpg&quot;&gt;All kinds of spaceships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thumbnails-visually.netdna-ssl.com/ThePlanets_5282a6d2111c5.jpg&quot;&gt;Relative size of the planets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interactive-data-stories&quot;&gt;Interactive Data Stories&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting things baout data design / visualization is how great it can be at telling stories. You might not look at a set of numbers in a spreadsheet and say. “Man, this looks like a great story” but really, that’s all it is. And if it isn’t telling a unique story, it’s helping advance or evolve storyline. It is the evidence needed to make you believe something, or put great weight on something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;politics&quot;&gt;Politics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guns.periscopic.com/?year=2013&quot;&gt;Guns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://drones.pitchinteractive.com/&quot;&gt;Drones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.therefugeeproject.org/&quot;&gt;The Refugee Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;social-commentary&quot;&gt;Social Commentary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://selfiecity.net/selfiexploratory/&quot;&gt;Selfie City&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;musical&quot;&gt;Musical&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mta.me/&quot;&gt;Mta.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.baroque.me/&quot;&gt;Baroque.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-driven-design&quot;&gt;Data Driven Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently data has had a huge impact on design. It has taken the form of collecting analytics with services like Google Analytics and Mixpanel. These metrics are collected and used to make more informed design decisions about everything from what color a button should be to an entire architectural do-over, to complete website redesigns. Data allows us to have more confidence in the decisions we are making about pieces of our designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/analytics/&quot;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mixpanel.com/report/475085/events/&quot;&gt;Mixpanel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optimizely.com/&quot;&gt;Optimizely&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clipping Masks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-time&quot;&gt;Work Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s work on project 2 for the rest of class. If you dont’ have to volley then you should use this time to gather resources for your next volley. Start planning ahead (even if you don’t know what it’s going to be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Visual-Display-Quantitative-Information/dp/0961392142/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1414551305&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=visual+display+of+quantitative&quot;&gt;Visual Display of Quantitative Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-02/&quot;&gt;COMPLETE Project 2 - Ping Pong&lt;/a&gt; – Due November 5th!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Modularity (pg 158 - 173)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STUDY&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/design/spec/material-design/&quot;&gt;Google Material Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-09</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-09</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>R-R-R-Remix</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1ZUAPdIwiwP-NG9e3ct6i9tJ0zbFOUtEEI0sLWW62d6Q/viewform&quot;&gt;Class Portfolios…WTH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Midterm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick Tip&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity / Project 2 Start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;midterm----&quot;&gt;Midterm ┬─┬﻿ ︵ /(.□. \）&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take the first 30-45-ish minutes to complete the Midterm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-remix&quot;&gt;The Remix&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A non-linear re-interpretation of a of a given work or media other than music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve heard of a remix before. It’s that version of a song that’s usually longer, more annoying, and bassier. Well, its roots are in music and back in the late 60’s and 70’s dancehall DJs would de-contsrturct popular music tracks and rebuild them to cater to their particular audiences. This reappropriation of other peoples sounds is what sparked the remix revolution. Remixes still permeate through the pop culture today, but, over the last 40 years the idea of the remix has been… remixed? o.O&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;remixing-in-pop-culture&quot;&gt;Remixing in Pop Culture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists do this thing a lot where they take some ideas from other artists and build ideas off of them. It’s not uncommon to see references of art history in modern art, or throwbacks to older songs in pop music. But some artists have taken this idea to a whole new level. Andy Warhol was particularly fond of this. Most of his work revolved around reappropriating consumer goods, or pop culture references by way of almost blantantly copying them, while simultaneously changing the context in which they are viewed (Art gallery walls instead of corner store shelves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/Marilyndiptych.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Andy Warhol loved remixes. He would re-appropriate modern objects and figures into pieces of pop art.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/remix-02.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://edelmangallery.com/exhibitions-and-projects/exhibition-pages/2014/sandro-miller-malkovich,-malkovich,-malkovich-homage-to-photographic-masters.html&quot;&gt;Sandro&lt;/a&gt; has re-created some of the masters, but with John Malkovich&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imitation is the sincerest form of flattery, or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;other-cool-things&quot;&gt;Other Cool Things&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thru-you.com/&quot;&gt;Thru-You&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/thruyou.png&quot; alt=&quot;Thru-YOu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0OK3axoNrrA&quot;&gt;Flappy Bird Remakes&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/week8/flappy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Flappy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;copyright--fair-use&quot;&gt;Copyright &amp;amp; Fair Use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One extremely clear distinction to make with all of this talk about remixing and reappropriating is that it is &lt;strong&gt;ABSOLUTELY NOT&lt;/strong&gt; synonymous with plagiarism. That is still very much illegal, and will infringe on most college rules and copyright laws. If you consider doing any remix-y type stuff there are a few super important things that you should study to save you from copyright infringement because going to jail is bad. The first is The Copyright Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Copyright Act of 1976&lt;/strong&gt; is a United States copyright law and remains the primary basis of copyright law in the United States, as amended by several later enacted copyright provisions. The Act spells out the basic rights of copyright holders, codified the doctrine of &quot;fair use,&quot; and for most new copyrights adopted a unitary term based on the date of the author's death rather than the prior scheme of fixed initial and renewal terms. It became Public Law number 94-553 on October 19, 1976 and went into effect on January 1, 1978. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright_Act_of_1976&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next is Fair Use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fair use&lt;/strong&gt; is a limitation and exception to the exclusive right granted by copyright law to the author of a creative work. In United States copyright law, fair use is a doctrine that permits limited use of copyrighted material without acquiring permission from the rights holders. Examples of fair use include commentary, search engines, criticism, parody, news reporting, research, teaching, library archiving and scholarship. It provides for the legal, unlicensed citation or incorporation of copyrighted material in another author's work under a four-factor balancing test. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_use&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomforsythe.com/&quot;&gt;Tom Forsythe&lt;/a&gt; got sued by Mattel over the use of Barbie dolls in his project “Food Chain Barbie” but the case was dropped by Mattel because his use of the Barbies fell under the ‘parody’ clause of the Fair Use Act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blending Modes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time--project-2---ping-pong&quot;&gt;Activity Time / Project 2 - Ping Pong&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is going to kick-off Project 2. We are going to do something similar to Layer Tennis but without the commentary, and competition. What exactly is Layer Tennis you might ask? Well… &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.layertennis.com/&quot;&gt;It’s this thing&lt;/a&gt; that Jim Coudal and friends started a while ago here in Chicago. It has gotten really popular within the community and they are now on the 4th Season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;Two competitors swap a file back and forth in real-time, adding to and embellishing the work. Each artist gets fifteen minutes to complete a “volley” and then we post that to the site live. A third participant, a writer, provides play-by-play commentary on the action as it happens.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to change the rules a little bit to make it better suited for our class. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-02/&quot;&gt;The Project 2 Page&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://everythingisaremix.info/&quot;&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/talks/kirby_ferguson_embrace_the_remix#t-556072&quot;&gt;Embrace the Remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-02/&quot;&gt;Start Project 2 - Mashup&lt;/a&gt; – Due November 5th!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Transparency (pg 146 - 157) and Texture (pg 52 - 69)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-08</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-08</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meaning &amp; Semiotics</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Critique&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Semiotics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;critique&quot;&gt;Critique&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s critique will be a bit different. We are going to pair up to critique 2 of the 5 sets of images. We will take 15 minutes to analyze and write about our partner’s images. After we write about them you will share your feedback with each other. &lt;em&gt;Ready&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Set&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Go&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;semiotics&quot;&gt;Semiotics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking semiotics is a fancy word for the study of signs. Well, that’s cool… But what’s a sign? Signs are actually fairly complex. They are made up of any number of components – words, sounds, body language and context. Combined these create a sweet visual language that help us navigate the world, or read a human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;Semioticians (yes there's a job for that) do this for a living.. They study signs and how they create meaning. They figure out how meaning can be derived from different cultural, or personal experience.&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;icon-index-and-symbols&quot;&gt;Icon, Index, and Symbols&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, since there are people devoted to studying semiotics, someone was bound to classify, and categorize this stuff. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Sanders_Peirce&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; was that guy back in the early 1900s &lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/58/Charles_Sanders_Peirce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This one guy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To say, therefore, that thought cannot happen in an instant, but requires a time, is but another way of saying that every thought must be interpreted in another, or that all thought is in signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;large-block-grid-3 small-block-grid-1&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Icon&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An Icon sign is a sign that resembles something, such as photographs of people. An icon can also be illustrative or diagrammatic, for example a ‘no-smoking’ sign.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Index&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An Index signs are signs where there is a direct link between the sign and the object. The majority of traffic signs are Index signs as they represent information which relates to a location (eg, a ‘slippery road surface’ sign placed on a road which is prone to flooding)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;Symbols&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A symbol has no logical meaning between it and the object. Unfortunately the web is littered with bad examples of this type of sign, but there are good ones - a homepage icon which is a house for example. Other off screen symbols which may help explain the difference are flags. Flags are symbols which represent countries or organisations. Again, the crossover to design and branding is very evident in these signs.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;signifier-vs-signified&quot;&gt;Signifier vs Signified&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also another, arguably simpler, way to classify signs. Signifier, and signified. Or basically what the sign looks like, and what the sign means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Signifier’&lt;/strong&gt; - what it looks like&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Signified’&lt;/strong&gt; - what it means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;group-activity-time&quot;&gt;Group Activity Time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media0.giphy.com/media/xco6aabVXUQzC/200.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
We are going to split up into 4 groups and research one of these 4 symbols / icons below. Create a simple presentation (using Illustrator or Photoshop) which covers the history of it, it’s classification, it’s signifier and signified. You will then share it with us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handicapped Icon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace Sign&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar Symbol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Red Cross Emblem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk about it’s origins, how did it become culturally or historically relevant?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s sign classification (Icon, Index, Symbol)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s Signifier (What form does it take)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s Signified (What concept does it represent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-tip&quot;&gt;Quick Tip!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Blend tool! This powerful tool allows us to merge different shapes and styles together either on a smooth path, or with a specified amount of steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;midterm--&quot;&gt;Midterm (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://media.giphy.com/media/2FazfWOd7WPJuYqHe/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Aww Shit&quot; /&gt;
Im so into reaction gifs this week. And yes, we have a midterm. It’s going to be really really awesome and fun. I’ve even got a sweet study guide for you to use too. &lt;a href=&quot;/study-guides/midterm-guide/&quot;&gt;You can find that sweet guide right here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thenounproject.com&quot;&gt;The Noun Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rEgxTKUP_WI&quot;&gt;Sweet Semiotics Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;READ&lt;/strong&gt; Layers (pg 126 - 145)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STUDY&lt;/strong&gt; For Midterm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-07</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-07</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Framing</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Composition &amp;amp; Cropping&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image &amp;amp; Canvas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tumblr.com/photo/1280/sealmaiden/660425083/1/tumblr_l34mioHhbi1qa4s0q&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Certain visual traces are like evidence. The event itself has passed but it has left information - marks, for example - and those marks are held there forever in time, like a photograph holds information as long as it lasts… It’s very mysterious to me to come upon something like that in reality and have it explain itself - to have it give evidence of what occurred then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figcaption&gt;- Kenneth Josephson&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;composing&quot;&gt;Composing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve already covered on some of this when we talked about fundamental design theories a few weeks ago when we talked about &lt;a href=&quot;/week/week-02/#gestalt-theory&quot;&gt;Gestalt&lt;/a&gt; theories. The great thing about these concepts is that they can be used in any visual, or graphic art. Be that Print, Design, Illustration, or Game. We will focus a little more on these concepts and how they relate to photographs (photoshop eh?) but keep in mind that these are essentially universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rule-of-thirds&quot;&gt;Rule of thirds&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rule of thirds is a framing concept that splits the frame vertically and horizontally 3 times creating 9 separate blocks. The most interesting part of this concept lies in how you use this grid. Science has proven, well that’s not totally true, that your pictures will be more compositionally pleasing if you align your subject on one of the intersecting points of your grid. Seems like a pretty rad and easy way to get some good snaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/rot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rule of thirds grid in action&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/rotsplit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;It can also be used to organize your frame&lt;a href=&quot;http://photography.tutsplus.com/articles/quick-tip-the-rule-of-thirds--photo-7796&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;crop-tool&quot;&gt;Crop Tool&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t always have to align your subjects to the rule of thirds grid in your camera though. The Photoshop crop tool has some great grid overlays that allow you to re-frame any image to be more aligned with a grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;image--canvas&quot;&gt;Image &amp;amp; Canvas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One insanely important piece to all of this is understanding image size constraints (File size, and physical pixel dimensions of images), and how the canvas size plays into all of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;image-size&quot;&gt;Image Size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Image &amp;gt; Image Size&lt;/code&gt; will bring up the image size window. There are a few more complex things in here that we won’t be covering. But lets turn our attention to the width x height x resolution. Any image in Photoshop is defined by these three characteristics. Just as a room has width x height x depth a photograph is structured in a very similar way. One important thing to note is that images should never be up-sampled (made larger) than they originally were. This will basically make the image look like garbage and you’ll be bummed. The resolution, measured in PPI (Pixels Per Inch), is another critical piece of the images size. The larger the resolution, the more detail the image has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/image-size.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;canvas-size&quot;&gt;Canvas Size&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Image &amp;gt; Canvas Size&lt;/code&gt; will open the Canvas Size dialog. Keep in mind that this is totally separate from image size, but can be used to make the area of the image larger or smaller. Imagine it just as it is described, like the canvas around a painting. Except you can grow or shrink this canvas willy nilly. This will never resize your image, but if you make the canvas smaller than your image it will basically crop it. Increasing the canvas size is really great when you want to add space around an image, or if you are creating a layout that needs extra margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week6/canvas-size.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google image search for some rad space image. Bring that image into photoshop and crop it align with a rule of thirds grid. Then we will add 100px to the canvas size of then image. And change the image size to be 80% of what it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://photography.tutsplus.com/articles/quick-tip-the-rule-of-thirds--photo-7796&quot;&gt;Rule of Thirds Quick Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vsco.co/vscocam&quot;&gt;VSCOcam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shootmanual.co/&quot;&gt;ShootManual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assignments/assignment-03.html&quot;&gt;Assignment 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read&lt;/strong&gt; Hierarchy (pg 114 - 125)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/Photoshop-tutorials/Honing-your-image/124096/140597-4.html&quot;&gt;Photoshop Tutorials - Watch all of section 6 starting with this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-06</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-06</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pixels</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/yu4CedbRRV&quot;&gt;Submit Your Class Portfolio Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Project 1 Presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intro to Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;intro-to-photoshop&quot;&gt;Intro to Photoshop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photoshop has long been the king of pixel manipulators. It has been man-handling those little digital squares since January of 1998. It is still considered THE premier digital photography application. Now, we also consider Photoshop to be an extremely powerful design tool. In fact many web and graphic designers use Photoshop to layout static comps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vector-vs-raster-bitmap&quot;&gt;Vector vs Raster (Bitmap)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know from Illustrator vector lines are extremely accurate and are drawn by math. With raster all lines, shapes, and images are drawn with little dots on the screen, pixels. On a large image the detail created with these pixels can make up a photographic image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/vector-raster.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This is what raster and vector look like @ 400% zoom.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rgb-colorspace&quot;&gt;RGB Colorspace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked a little about Illustrator’s colorspace defaults to CMYK (subtractive color). Photoshop is on the other end and defaults to RGB. Primarily because photography deals with light (additive color). You’ll see this if you open up the Channels palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/cmykrgb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This is what raster and vector look like @ 400% zoom.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-of-photoshop&quot;&gt;Benefits of Photoshop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the major benefits of Photoshop vs Vector programs really comes down to it’s ability to edit raster images. It makes designing photographic layouts much easier since you have the ability to edit the photos and lay them out in the same application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/mailchimp_redesign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mailchimps last redesign would have been a pain without something like Photoshop.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, on the flip side, images contain a whole lot more data than vector files so your file sizes start to get significantly larger. I’ve had comps that will get well above the 1GB file size range. That’s not always fun when you have a deadline, and it takes 10 minutes to save a file :\&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;photoshop-workspace&quot;&gt;Photoshop Workspace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at some of the tools we’ve got in the Photoshop UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/ps-107.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The photoshop Toolbar. LOLJKROFLMAO.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JK, that’s the Photoshop 1.0 UI. It’s changed a lot, for realsies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/week5/photoshop-tools.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Phew, I found them. This is what PS CC looks like. CS6 will look a little bit different.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/week5/ps-activity-01.psd&quot;&gt;Download this file&lt;/a&gt;, we will work from this and learn about some of the more important photoshop tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;photoshop-alternatives&quot;&gt;Photoshop Alternatives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pretty rad alternatives to Photoshop. &lt;strong&gt;HUGE DISCLAIMER: I don’t know all these apps so if you want to use them you will be kind of on your own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pixelmator.com/&quot;&gt;Pixelmator (Mac only)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gimp.org/&quot;&gt;GIMP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bohemiancoding.com/sketch/&quot;&gt;Sketch (Mac Only)&lt;/a&gt; - This is not a photoeditor, but it’s the application that I use for UI design. It’s pretty rad, and is great for webdesign .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No Assignments Just reading and tutorials to make you more awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Framing (pg 100 - 113)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lynda.com/Photoshop-tutorials/Navigating-your-image/124096/140551-4.html&quot;&gt;Photoshop Tutorials - Watch all of section 2 starting with this one&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-05</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-05</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&lt; H T M L &gt;</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;agenda&quot;&gt;Agenda&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;H T M L&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;C S S&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start Class portfolios / Show me some Project 1 stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;h-y-p-e-r-t-e-x-t-m-a-r-k-u-p-l-a-n-g-u-a-g-e&quot;&gt;H Y P E R T E X T M A R K U P L A N G U A G E&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-basix&quot;&gt;The Basix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language) is a markup language for the web. All websites you visit are built with HTML, and it is nothing more than a dumbed down word processor. Srsly, that’s how HTML was created, to share scientific documents between labs that were around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.isoc-ny.org/p2/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/timbernerslee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;This dude invented what you know as the World Wide Web (does anyone call it that?)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;let’s watch a quick video that will dive into ta bit of the history of HTML and the web. &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/12020260&quot;&gt;Video Time&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;html-breakdown&quot;&gt;HTML Breakdown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific version of HTML we are learning is 5. And HTML5 is actually pretty simple and HTML elements are pretty basic and easy to remember. Say you have a big block of text, a paragraph!, you would wrap that block of text in tags that look like this &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;BIG BLOCK OF TEXT&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; in this example is an HTML tag. All HTML tags start with &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;TAG&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and close with &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/TAG&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Let’s take a look at some &lt;code&gt;CODE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is literally all you need to create an HTML document. This is the start of every single website on the internet. What’s your favorite website? I’ll bet it uses this format. And there are all kinds of tags. &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;section&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;header&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;nav&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;video&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and that’s just a few. I bet you could guess what some of those do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That example above won’t display anything when we put it into the browser because there’s no content. So lets add a few other things. How about an image and some paragraph text?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; Here&amp;#39;s some paragraph text. Such compelling. So paragraph. Wow.&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://placekitten.com/600/350&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;/&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;c-a-s-c-a-d-i-n-g-s-t-y-l-e-s-h-e-e-t-s&quot;&gt;C A S C A D I N G S T Y L E S H E E T S&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet, we’ve made a dope HTML Document! But, man, it’s friggen ugly right? Well that’s where CSS comes in. CSS allows you to attach some nice styles to your HTML elements. If you think about a house, HTML is the walls and CSS is the paint. Say you want the background to be hot pink, because hot pink. And we want the text to be blue, since it will make our brains melt. But how does it look? CSS can attach itself to specific HTML elements to make them look different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECTOR { DECLARATION – PROPERTY : VALUE }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;pink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;p&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;blue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-specific&quot;&gt;Getting specific&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While styling tags is all cool and stuff, the real power of CSS comes in with Classes and IDs. These are semantic identifiers for HTML tags. For example. If I had a block of text that we wanted to be purple but we didn’t want every single &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag to be purple we could give that tag a class of purple. And it would look like this &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p class=&quot;purple-text&quot;&amp;gt;THIS IS PURPLE TEXT&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Then go into your CSS file and add this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;.purple-text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;pink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the one weird thing about this is there is a &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; before the words &lt;code&gt;purple-text&lt;/code&gt;. That &lt;code&gt;.&lt;/code&gt; defines a CSS class. Try and keep you classes semantic and easy to understand. When you see purple text in a CSS file it’s pretty clear what that does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;activity-time&quot;&gt;ACTIVITY TIME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s do this next section together. Download &lt;a href=&quot;/files/week4/class-site-template.zip&quot;&gt;this file&lt;/a&gt;, and open up the &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file in any text editor. We will start creating our class portfolios. WOOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;choose-your-path-to-deploy-or-not-deploy&quot;&gt;Choose your path. To deploy or not deploy.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, since we aren’t going to get a whole lot deeper with HTML I don’t think it’s 100% necessary for all of you to create your own HTML pages. However, I will support your decision to do so. I’ll also give you the option to create a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;tumblr&lt;/a&gt; for yourself / this class. So if you are making a new tumblr account go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tumblr.com/register&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt;. If you have a tumblr account already, create a new blog for this class in the dashboard. If you plan to create your own HTML site KEEP ON READIN’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://imamp.colum.edu/mediawiki/index.php/FTP#IAM_tech_staff_recommends_connecting_to_our_server_with_FTPs_please_see_the_FTPs_tutorial_IAM_FTPS_Tutorial&quot;&gt;Re-learn to FTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you are on the network, and on a PC, go to your Z drive. This is your space on IAM servers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In your pub folder, create a subfolder called DID.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload all the files we worked on to that folder.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to your URL&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Upload or add your work to your portfolio! This is a graded piece of the class and will be required to upload your work your portfolios. Add the assignments you’ve already done with a &lt;strong&gt;title&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;short description&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;homework&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/courses/web-beginner-en-HZA3b/0/1?curriculum_id=50579fb998b470000202dc8b&quot;&gt;Do this Codecadmy activity to upgrade your HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read: Figure / Ground (pg 84 - 99)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/project-01.html&quot;&gt;PROJECT 01&lt;/a&gt; – Next week we will present your first Projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-resources&quot;&gt;Additional Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;Code Cademy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.teamtreehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Treehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codeschool.com/&quot;&gt;CodeSchool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/HTML-CSS-Design-Build-Websites/dp/1118008189/ref=sr_1_1/191-9246497-5557808?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1411606712&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=html+css&quot;&gt;Great HTML &amp;amp; CSS book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://html5boilerplate.com/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-04</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://teach.trvr.co/week/week-04</guid>
        
        
        <category>week</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
